<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<resources>

    <string-array name="historical_names">
        <item>The Pyramids of Giza</item>
        <item>Luxor\'s Karnak Temple</item>
        <item>Abu Simbel temples</item>
        <item>Abydos\' Temple of Osiris</item>
        <item>Valley of the Kings</item>
    </string-array>

    <string-array name="historical_summaries">
        <item>The last surviving of the Seven Wonders of the Ancient World, the Pyramids of Giza are one of the world\'s most recognisable landmarks. Built as tombs for the mighty Pharaohs and guarded by the enigmatic Sphinx, Giza\'s pyramid complex has awed travelers down through the ages and had archaeologists (and a fair few conspiracy theorists) scratching their heads over how they were built for centuries. Today, these megalithic memorials to dead kings are still as wondrous a sight as they ever were. An undeniable highlight of any Egypt trip, Giza\'s pyramids should not be missed.</item>
        <item>Karnak Temple is a vast temple complex in Luxor dedicated primarily to Amun and dating from as early as 2000 BC. It is an impressive sight, and second only to the Great Pyramids in popularity.\n\nThe Karnak temple complex is huge, covering a site almost a mile by two miles in area. There are over 25 temples and chapels in the complex, including separate shrines for the three boats that took the statues of the gods on their annual trip on the flooding Nile. Sanctuaries, obelisks, and groups of columns all feature accounts of the heroic deeds of the sponsoring pharoah.\n\nThe key difference between Karnak and most of the other temples and sites in Egypt is the length of time over which it was developed and used. Approximately 30 pharaohs contributed to the buildings, enabling it to reach a size, complexity and diversity not seen elsewhere. Few of the individual features of Karnak are unique, but the sheer size and number of features makes it one of the most impressive temple complexes in Egypt.\n\nThe Karnak complex includes several of the finest examples of ancient Egyptian design and architecture. Among them are the Hypostyle Hall, considered one of the world\'s great architectural achievements. It is filled with 134 enormous pillars, the highest 70 feet tall, and each about 45 feet around. The hall covers an area of 64,586 sq ft.\n\nThe most spectacular of the temples at Karnak is the Temple of Amun (Amun\'s Precinct), the only section open to the public. This is entered via the Avenue of the Sphinxes, or Sacred Way, that once stretched the two miles from Karnak to Luxor Temple.\n\nThe Obelisk of Thutmose I, a 22m (71ft) monument, is the only one of four original obelisks that is still standing.</item>
        <item>Even in a country festooned with temples, Abu Simbel is something special. This is Ramses II\'s great temple, adorned with colossal statuary standing guard outside, and with an interior sumptuously decorated with wall paintings. Justly famous for its megalithic proportions, Abu Simbel is also known for the incredible feat, which saw the entire temple moved from its original setting - set to disappear under the water because of the Aswan dam - during the 1960s in a massive UNESCO operation that took four years.</item>
        <item>Dusty Abydos town wouldn\‘t make much of a rating on the tourism radar if it wasn\’t for the incredible temple on its doorstep. Abydos\' Temple of Osiris is one of ancient Egypt\'s most fascinating artistic treasures. Its chunky columns and walls, covered in beautiful hieroglyphics and intricate paintings, are spell-binding sights, and even better, you can admire them without the crowds as despite its dazzling beauty, it receives few visitors compared to the temples in nearby Luxor.</item>
        <item>On the west bank of the Nile lies the Valley of the Kings, a necropolis used to house the bodies and belonging of many pharaohs from Thutmose I all the way until Ramesses X or XI. There are 63 tombs in the area, built there between 1539 BC to around 1075 BC.\n\nThe Valley of the Kings is one of the earliest examples of a necropolis, (literally, a ‘city of the dead\‘). A veritable burial ground of the great pharaohs and noblemen of Egypt for a period of time that spans 500 years, the Valley of the Kings remains one of the richest sources of Ancient Egyptian history.\n\nProperly referred to by scholars as ‘The Great and Majestic Necropolis of the Millions of Years of the Pharaoh, Life, Strength, Health in the West of Thebes\’, or ‘The Great Field\'.\n\nIn the East Valley, in 1922, Howard Carter found what was labeled KV62: the tomb of Tutankhamun.\n\nWhile many of the tombs and chambers in the area were sacked by thieves, this one was intact and stocked full with treasures. Valuable things as jewelry, statues, weapons and the Pharaoh\'s chariot, were valuable finds, but the real treasure was the magnificently decorated sarcophagus, with the young king\'s remains inside.</item>
    </string-array>

    <string-array name="natural_names">
        <item>White Desert</item>
        <item>Siwa Oasis</item>
        <item>Alexandria</item>
        <item>The Red Sea Coast</item>
        <item>Hurghada</item>
        <item>Aswan</item>
        <item>Berenice</item>
    </string-array>

    <string-array name="natural_summaries">
        <item>Egypt\'s kookiest natural wonder is the White Desert where surreally shaped chalk mountains have created what looks like a snowy wonderland in the middle of the arid sand. The landscapes here look like something out of a science fiction movie with blindingly white boulders and iceberg-like pinnacles. For desert fans and adventurers, this is the ultimate weird playground, while anybody who\'s had their fill of temples and tombs will enjoy this spectacular natural scenery.</item>
        <item>Way out west, Siwa is the tranquil tonic to the hustle of Egypt\'s cities. This gorgeous little oasis, surrounded by date palm plantations and numerous fresh water springs, is one of the Western Desert\'s most picturesque spots. The town is centered around the ruins of a vast mud-brick citadel that dominates the view. This is a top spot to wind down and go slow for a few days as well as being an excellent base from which to plan adventures into the surrounding desert.</item>
        <item>The most European of Egypt\'s cities, Alexandria has a history that not many others can match. Founded by Alexander the Great, home of Cleopatra, and razzmatazz renegade city of the Mediterranean for much of its life, this seaside city has an appealing days-gone-by atmosphere that can\'t be beaten. Although today, there are few historic remnants of its illustrious past - feted in songs and books - this is a place made for aimless strolling along the seashore Corniche, café-hopping, and souk shopping.</item>
        <item>A highlight of many a traveller to Egypt, Sharm el Sheik is a holiday resort filled with luxury hotels, casinos, nightclubs and tourists getting their sun, sea and sand fix. Sharm el Sheikh holidays are very popular although the real beauty of this area is the Red Sea. The Red Sea has clear azure waters and an incredible amount of exotic fish and coral – which is why is so highly regarded as a diving destination. In fact, it arguably offers some of the best diving and snorkelling experiences in the world.</item>
        <item>Hurghada is a stunning resort town located on the Northeast coast of Egypt, just below the Gulf of Suez. A better summary of Hurghada would be the Hurghada Riviera as it stretches for 40 miles along the Red Sea Coast and is home to many luxurious resorts. Originally a fishing town, Hurghada has grown quickly over the past few decades to become something of a tourist hotspot. There are many excellent restaurants, tourist attractions and accommodation options to choose from in the region.\n\nThis includes luxurious resorts like Makadi Bay, Sahl Hasheesh and El Gouna which make it the perfect location if you want to be pampered. However, it is the stunning natural beauty of Hurghada that is the highlight of this destination. There are many pristine beaches to explore with bright white sand and crystal clear water. The coastline is also dotted with coral reefs, which is the reason why Hurghada is one of the most popular locations for diving and snorkelling in Egypt. If you intend on exploring the reefs, be sure to check out Careless Reef, Giftun Islands, and Omo Gamaar. You can also swim with the dolphins off the coast of the Aden Beach Resort. If you don\'t feel like getting wet, you can also check out the sea creatures at Hurghada Grand Aquarium and Shaab Abu Ramada Aquarium or take a submarine tour. Finally, be sure to visit the Eastern Arabian Desert. There are many tours available for activities including quad biking, and visiting historical sites.</item>
        <item>Aswan is a historic city on the southern end of the Nile River. One of the must-see cities in Egypt, it is a gorgeous metropolis set in an idyllic location with a pristine natural environment and scenic views. In addition to being situated in a picturesque part of Egypt, the city itself is and packed with many amazing ancient buildings that give it a delightful ambience. Aswan is one of the oldest cities in Egypt and has a rich history dating back many thousands of years. There are many beautiful locations to visit including the Aswan Botanical Gardens, Ruins of Abu, Tombs of the Nobles, and Elephantine Island. It is the perfect location for learning more about Egypt\'s rich culture and vast history.</item>
        <item>The ancient city of Berenice is another popular location in Egypt for tourists interested in experiencing the most beautiful parts of Egypt. Located in the Red Sea Governorate, Berenice was founded as a trading port in 275BC and quickly became an important economic centre in the region. One of the most exciting locations to visit near Berenice is the Temple of Semiramis built by Trajan and Tiberius. This large Roman temple is in excellent condition and is one of the most impressive sights in the region. The outer walls of the temple are adorned with various artworks including depictions of Emperor Tiberius before the god Min and the nearby the deity of the Green Mines (located nearby).\n\nThe coast of Berenice has many pristine natural bays and coves to enjoy. You can also explore the stunning island of Zabargad, which was previously mined for a semi-precious gem named olivine. There are many breathtaking views to enjoy in this area and plenty of marine life. It\'s also a great place to go snorkelling or diving or to simply relax on one of the many beaches.</item>
    </string-array>

    <string-array name="hotels_names">
        <item>The Nile Ritz-Carlton</item>
        <item>Royal Maxim Palace Kempinski</item>
        <item>Marriott Mena House</item>
        <item>Four Seasons</item>
        <item>Kempinski Nile Hotel</item>
    </string-array>

    <string-array name="hotels_summaries">
        <item>Located in the heart of Cairo lies the iconic Nile Ritz-Carlton Cairo, located between the Nile river, Tahrir square and adjacent to the Egyptian Museum. The hotel features panoramic views of the Nile corniche and only a stroll across to Qasr El Nil Bridge and Cairo Opera House. Guests can enjoy the free WiFi in the public areas as well as in the room.\n\nSpacious and stylish, the rooms offer working desks. All rooms come with a TV. You will find a coffee machine in the room. Each room is fitted with a private bathroom that consists of a lavish bath tub and a walk-in shower. For your comfort, you will find bath robes, slippers and a hair dryer.\n\nThe hotel offers a Casino and night life experience. More than nine distinctive restaurants and bars promise an unforgettable getaway. Bab El-Sharq is the signature Arabian restaurant offering Shisha and daily entertainment, Vivo the Italian restaurant overlooks the Nile and Cairo tower and Nox offers a nightlife experience from the rooftop overlooking entire Cairo.\n\nThe hotel also offers 24/7 fitness center, a lavish spa and a year-round sunny outdoor pool.\n\nKhan El Khalili Bazaar is 0.6 mi away from The Nile Ritz-Carlton, Cairo, while The Cairo Tower is 0.8 mi away. The nearest airport is Cairo Airport, 16 mi from the property.\n\nThis property also has one of the top-rated locations in Cairo! Guests are happier about it compared to other properties in the area.\n\nCouples in particular like the location – they rated it 9.1 for a two-person trip.\n\nThis property is also rated for the best value in Cairo! Guests are getting more for their money when compared to other properties in this city.</item>
        <item>Royal Maxim Palace Kempinski Cairo is a 5-star hotel that offers luxury accommodations in the center of Cairo. It features an all year-round outdoor pool, a palatial inspired courtyard, and a modern fitness center. Cairo International Airport is a 15-minute drive away.\n\nEvery elegant room comes with a flat-screen TV and a seating area to relax in after a busy day. Rooms have views of the pool, garden or courtyard. Each room includes a private bathroom with a bath or shower, bathrobes, slippers and free toiletries.\n\nGuests can enjoy a wide array of culinary delights at one of the 9 restaurants and bars. All day snacks and refreshments are also served at the Royal Club Lounge.\n\nResense Spa is the first luxury European spa in the city offering a unique relaxing experience where guests can rejuvenate with multiple treatments and sessions.\n\nSpecial events can be arranged at the largest ballroom in Egypt, The Excelsior. Cairo Festival City is 4.3 mi from Royal Maxim Palace Kempinski Cairo, while Cairo Intel Conference Center is 6.2 mi away. The nearest airport is Cairo Airport, 3.7 mi from Royal Maxim Palace Kempinski Cairo.\n\nNew Cairo City is a great choice for travelers interested in restaurants, food and shopping.\n\nCouples in particular like the location – they rated it 8.0 for a two-person trip.\n\nThis property is also rated for the best value in Cairo! Guests are getting more for their money when compared to other properties in this city.</item>
        <item>Overlooking the Great Pyramids of Giza, Marriott Mena House, Cairo is surrounded by 40 acres of green gardens and has a spa, fitness center and a pool. The rooms are decorated with handcrafted furniture.\n\nAll accommodations at Marriott Mena House, Cairo have air conditioning and include luxurious fabrics, a seating area and LCD TV. Each room and suite has a spacious private bathroom with a bathrobe and slippers.\n\nBreakfast is available in the dining room facing the garden.\n\nDining choices range from Italian specialties at Alfredo Restaurant, while Daily Buffet Breakfast and unforgettable vistas with its cocktails served at 139 Pavilion.\n\nRecreational Facilities include a heated swimming pool tucked away in the landscape gardens.\n\nThe Giza Pyramids are less than half a kilometer from the Marriott Mena House. The concierge can arrange horse and camel rides to the pyramids. Cairo Airport is 19 mi away.\n\nGiza is a great choice for travelers interested in monuments, museums and history.\n\nThis property also has one of the top-rated locations in Cairo! Guests are happier about it compared to other properties in the area.\n\nCouples in particular like the location – they rated it 9.2 for a two-person trip.\n\nThis property is also rated for the best value in Cairo! Guests are getting more for their money when compared to other properties in this city.</item>
        <item>Enjoying impressive views of Cairo\'s skyline and the Pyramids, The Four Seasons Hotel in Cairo\'s Gizah district features a full-service spa and outdoor pool. The Nile River is just 100 m away.\n\nAll rooms at The First Residence Cairo feature stylish colonial décor and panoramic city or Nile views. They are equipped with a flat-screen TV, a BOSE entertainment system and a DVD player.\n\nFacilities include a top-floor spa offering a wide range of health and beauty treatments. It also features a sauna, hot tub and fitness center. Guests can also try their luck at the on-site casino.\n\nLight refreshments are offered at the Tea Lounge. Guests can feast on traditional Syrian/Lebanese cuisine that is served pool side in Aura. There is also La Gourmandize which is a trendy brasserie eatery located in the heart of The First Mall.\n\nFour Seasons Cairo At The First Residence offers a room service, car rental services and airport limousine services. Four Seasons Cairo At The First Residence is just a 2-minute walk from Cairo\'s historic Zoological and Botanical Gardens. Cairo International Airport is 16 mi from the property.\n\nGiza is a great choice for travelers interested in monuments, museums and history.\n\nCouples in particular like the location – they rated it 8.3 for a two-person trip.\n\nThis property is also rated for the best value in Cairo! Guests are getting more for their money when compared to other properties in this city.</item>
        <item>Located in Cairo\‘s affluent Garden City district, Kempinski Hotel offers luxurious rooms on the shores of the Nile River. It features a wellness center and a rooftop swimming pool.\n\nEach of Kempinski\’s rooms offer free WiFi and high definition LCD TVs with satellite channels and a free mini-bar with soft drinks. For guests\‘ comfort, it offers a butler service and pillow concierge. The bathrooms are marbled.\n\nKempinski\’s full-service spa and wellness center offers complimentary hot tubs, steam rooms, and saunas. Guests can also enjoy professional massages, or cool off in the outdoor swimming pool on the hotel\‘s rooftop.\n\nNile Hotel Kempinski features a variety of restaurants and bars, including the Osmanly offering Ottoman cuisine. Guests can also enjoy French dining at the Blue Restaurant or drink champagne at the Floor 10.\n\nKempinski Nile Hotel is 5 minutes\’ walk from downtown Cairo and from the Egyptian Museum. Cairo International Airport is 16 mi away, and the Pyramids of Giza and the Cairo Citadel are 20 minutes away by car.\n\nGarden City is a great choice for travelers interested in nightlife, museums and entertainment.\n\nCouples in particular like the location – they rated it 8.4 for a two-person trip.</item>
    </string-array>

    <string-array name="restaurants_names">
        <item>Sequoia, Zamalek</item>
        <item>Il Piccolo Mondo, Le Pacha 1901, Zamalek</item>
        <item>Abou El Sid, Zamalek</item>
        <item>OAK Grill, Conrad Hotel, Nile Corniche</item>
        <item>L\'Asiatique, Le Pacha 1901, Zamalek</item>
    </string-array>
    
    <string-array name="restaurants_summaries">
        <item>The great vibes and stunning view of this place is still unmatched anywhere else in the city. You\'re basically surrounded by the Nile from all angles. Their menu is very diverse and they serve alcoholic beverages and shisha. What more could you ask for?</item>
        <item>This is one of Le Pacha boat\'s classics. They serve authentic Italian food the right way! The restaurant design imitates the Piazza San Carlo in Italy which makes it quite unique. You can even write a note or make a drawing on the walls, that are already covered in writings from previous customers, and leave a memory that will last a lifetime.</item>
        <item>This is a Cairo classic. Make sure you head to the original branch in Zamalek and transport back to Egypt in the 1940s. Abou El Sid offers a full blown Egyptian culinary experience ranging from Molokheya with rabbits to pigeons to Om Ali.</item>
        <item>This fancy-pants restaurant in Conrad Hotel, even though slightly overpriced, is well worth a visit, at least as a one time thing to celebrate your partner\'s birthday or your recent promotion. We highly recommend the rib-eye steak and the vanilla bean crème brulèe.</item>
        <item>This is another Le Pacha classic, which also recently opened in 6 October. It was chosen as Africa\'s best restaurant years in a row a few years back and it truly is worthy of the title. This sleek and secluded restaurant serves up some of the best sushi and Pan-Asian cuisine in town, so dress up and head down there with your family and friends for a dinner to remember.</item>
    </string-array>

</resources>
